<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>A blog about life</title>
        <link>http://canena.de/posts</link>
        <description>Life/Music/Art/Code/Stuff</description>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2019 12:54:45 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs>
        <generator>Elmstatic</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <image>
            <title>A blog about life</title>
            <url>http://canena.de/img/logo.png</url>
            <link>http://canena.de/posts</link>
        </image>
        <copyright>© 2019 CANENA - All rights reserved</copyright>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Making a habit of making a habit]]></title>
            <link>http://canena.de/posts/2015-08-04-making-a-habit-of-making-a-habit</link>
            <guid>http://canena.de/posts/2015-08-04-making-a-habit-of-making-a-habit</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Aug 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
Making a habit of making a habit

Lately I’ve been thinking a lot about writing and whether I could do it myself. “Yes, I could do it if I really wanted” is what I’d tell the spectre in the mirror. I just always had the nagging feeling that I didn’t care enough so the outcome surely wouldn’t be worth the digital ink. I’d be jealous of the interesting stuff people have to say and the sense of style that would let me almost inhale their stories at times. Why is it that I couldn’t start something?...]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Hello Living Styleguide]]></title>
            <link>http://canena.de/posts/2017-01-18-hello-living-style-guide</link>
            <guid>http://canena.de/posts/2017-01-18-hello-living-style-guide</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[Note that this styleguide has been moved over from an older version of the blog so this approach does not necessarily represent the way the markup is structured anymore. It shows, however, that embedding alternative styles into an existing page is a breeze when employing BEM blocks. The old styles literally live side-by-side with the new ones and the mild namespacing via ui-theme allows for selective theming on a per-subtree-basis.

This is the living documentation for my own little set of respo...]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[Epic Links]]></title>
            <link>http://canena.de/posts/2017-03-20-epic-links</link>
            <guid>http://canena.de/posts/2017-03-20-epic-links</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
A collection of links that I found useful, inspired me and may bring you enjoyment and/or enlightenment as well.

Disclaimer

I'm not in any way affiliated with the following links, I just find them useful, delightful, funny...

Useful Tools

https://caniuse.com
https://css-tricks.com

Favorite Developer Blogs

https://ayende.com
http://blog.ploeh.dk/
https://cuttingedge.it/blogs/steven/
https://ericlippert.com

Daily Dose

https://aeon.co
https://news.ycombinator.com/newest
https://www.reddit....]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[An Elm to the Past]]></title>
            <link>http://canena.de/posts/2018-02-24-an-elm-to-the-past</link>
            <guid>http://canena.de/posts/2018-02-24-an-elm-to-the-past</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
This blog post compiles the advice I posted in
a discussion on Elm Discourse
on support of Elm for older browsers and is pretty much reproduced verbatim, thanks to the power Markdown.

I've put all the information in here to good use so head to
https://github.com/mfeineis/elm-legacy-browser-setup
if you want to see some code right away. I even managed to bring support for IE8+, which I didn't expect, tbh.

Original Post Gist

"Is there an official list of supported browsers for Elm? If not, wha...]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[TypeScript vs the Real World]]></title>
            <link>http://canena.de/posts/2019-03-04-typescript-vs-the-real-world</link>
            <guid>http://canena.de/posts/2019-03-04-typescript-vs-the-real-world</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
This started out as a YouTube comment on a talk about TypeScript that got out of control in scope so I created a blog post instead.

Go watch Why I Was Wrong About TypeScript.

Questions You Should Be Asking Yourself

The speaker largely highlights positive aspects of TypeScript. How many technologies do you know that have no flaws? TS obviously has a lot of benefits but here are some questions I would put up for discussion that nobody seems to talk about:

1) How accurate do you think bolted o...]]></description>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[A blog about life]]></title>
            <link>http://canena.de/posts/undefined-undefined</link>
            <guid>http://canena.de/posts/undefined-undefined</guid>
            <pubDate>Invalid Date</pubDate>
            <description><![CDATA[
...]]></description>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>